<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dplyr on Michael Lee</title>
    <link>/tags/dplyr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dplyr on Michael Lee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/dplyr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dominance of Jonathan Taylor: Wisconsin Rushers in Context</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-01-28-wisconsin-rushing-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2019-01-28-wisconsin-rushing-history/</guid>
      <description>Hot Take Alert🔥 Jonathan Taylor is on pace to be the greatest running back in Wisconsin football history 🔥
Over the previous three decades Wisconsin has retained several elite rushers (and offensive lines) to amass several conference championships and Rose Bowl appearances. Even when acknowledging Taylor’s case as a serious Heisman candidate in each of his first two years, proclaiming him the presumptive best running back in Wisconsin football history still feels like a bold proclamation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seasonal Virgin River Narrows Discharge</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-04-16-hiking-the-narrows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2018-04-16-hiking-the-narrows/</guid>
      <description>This April I’m visiting Zion National Park, one of North America’s most interesting locations to explore geologic formations. One such venue in the park is an iconic hike referred to as The Narrows:
The Narrows in Zion National Park
It’s surely even more sensational in person.
Unfortunately, there’s a catch: the Virgin River, a Colorado river tributary that shaped the distinct rock walls of The Narrows, has seasonal water level changes that can force hikers to trek waist deep in the river or close the route entirely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Minor League Similarity Scores</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-03-25-milb-similarity-scores/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2015-03-25-milb-similarity-scores/</guid>
      <description>There are some people who see baseball players that way-each one is unique, absolutely not interchangeable with another. I don&#39;t deny the validity of that approach-but if you take that tack, then you can&#39;t turn around and argue that your player should be in the Hall of Fame because his numbers are just as good as this other player&#39;s. &#34;Similarity&#34; is a complex concept, and two players who are not statistically similar may be profoundly similar in some other way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>