<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data on Michael Lee</title>
    <link>/tags/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data on Michael Lee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>International Activities Program Highlights - PISA</title>
      <link>/projects/2019-12-02-iap-pisa-summary-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/projects/2019-12-02-iap-pisa-summary-release/</guid>
      <description>Background (via https://nces.ed.gov/surveys/pisa/) The Program for International Student Assessment (PISA) is an international assessment that measures 15-year-old students&amp;rsquo; reading, mathematics, and science literacy every three years. First conducted in 2000, the major domain of study rotates between reading, mathematics, and science in each cycle. PISA also includes measures of general or cross-curricular competencies, such as collaborative problem solving. By design, PISA emphasizes functional skills that students have acquired as they near the end of compulsory schooling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Activities Program Highlights - ICILS</title>
      <link>/projects/2019-11-05-iap-icils-summary-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/projects/2019-11-05-iap-icils-summary-release/</guid>
      <description>Background (via https://nces.ed.gov/surveys/icils/) The International Computer and Information Literacy Study (ICILS) is a computer-based international assessment of 8th-grade students&amp;rsquo; capacities &amp;ldquo;to use information communications technologies (ICT) productively for a range of different purposes, in ways that go beyond a basic use of ICT&amp;rdquo; (Fraillon et al., 2018). First conducted in 2013, ICILS assessed students’ computer and information literacy (CIL) with an emphasis on the use of computers as information-seeking, management, and communication tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights on Diversifying the Educator Workforce - Teacher Diversity Tool</title>
      <link>/projects/2019-12-30-teacher-student-shiny-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/projects/2019-12-30-teacher-student-shiny-application/</guid>
      <description>Background The Center on Great Teachers and Leader&#39;s (GTL Center) mission is to support states and districts in their efforts to grow, respect, and retain great teachers and leaders for all students, especially those from disadvantaged backgrounds.
The GTL Center has an Excel data tool that is used to reveal insights about the diversity of the educator workforce at the state, district, school, or EPP level. One component of this tool that was missing was a method to map and explore teacher and student ethnicity data by school district.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Activities Program Highlights - TALIS</title>
      <link>/projects/2019-06-28-iap-talis-summary-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/projects/2019-06-28-iap-talis-summary-release/</guid>
      <description>Background (via https://nces.ed.gov/surveys/talis/) The Teaching and Learning International Survey (TALIS) is a survey about teachers, teaching, and learning environments. Sponsored by the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD), TALIS is composed of two questionnaires—one for teachers and one for their principals—which ask questions about their backgrounds, their work environments, professional development, and their beliefs and attitudes about teaching. TALIS is unique because it is the only comparative international education study that collects data on nationally representative samples of teachers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EdSurvey - R package (CRAN)</title>
      <link>/projects/2017-06-03-edsurvey-r-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/projects/2017-06-03-edsurvey-r-package/</guid>
      <description>Package Description The EdSurvey package is a tool to read and analyze functions for education surveys and assessments data from the National Center for Education Statistics, including the National Assessment of Educational Progress (NAEP). Due to the large file sizes and complex formatting of NCES data sets, the package offers user-friendly methods to format and conduct statisitical analyses with a small memory footprint.
For more info:  https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/EdSurvey/index.html http://www.air.org/project/nces-data-r-project-edsurvey  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAEPprimer - R package (CRAN)</title>
      <link>/projects/2017-06-03-naepprimer-r-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/projects/2017-06-03-naepprimer-r-package/</guid>
      <description>Package Description The NAEP Primer package contains a random mini-sample of real data from the 2005 grade 8 mathematics assessment that have been approved for public use. This includes two data files, as well as a system control file that corresponds to each data file to read in and format for further processing. The NAEP Primer is designed to simplify access to the NAEP database and make its technologies more user-friendly in NAEP data analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NBA Draft Odds Plot</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-06-01-nba-draft-odds-plot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2016-06-01-nba-draft-odds-plot/</guid>
      <description>Original Source
I was scrolling twitter and noticed this tweet from David Sparks - Director of Basketball Analytics for the Boston Celtics:
With his obligatory shoutouts to Hadley Wickham and BoB Rudis, I felt compelled to reproduce the plot in RStudio and get some ggplot2 code out there open-sourcing his work.
Package Dependencies and Data
The data was generated using simulations of the NBA Draft lottery, which resulted in some peculiar distributions compared to the raw lottery odds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sabr - R package</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-05-28-sabr-r-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2016-05-28-sabr-r-package/</guid>
      <description>The sabr package connects the Lahman SQL Database with functions used in calculating offensive performance in the MLB, namely wOBA. Created by Tom Tango and popularized in The Book: Playing the Percentages in Baseball, wOBA uses yearly MLB performance to weigh offensive measures relative to league value. This package offers the following capabilities:
 Retrieves the most up-to-date wOBA measures from 1871-2015 Queries yearly and career offensive performance from the Lahman SQL database Calculates a player&#39;s seasonal wOBA performance  Installation: Download the latest development version from github:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sabr - R package (GitHub)</title>
      <link>/projects/2016-05-28-sabr-r-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/projects/2016-05-28-sabr-r-package/</guid>
      <description>The sabr package connects the Lahman SQL Database with functions used in calculating offensive performance in the MLB, namely wOBA. Created by Tom Tango and popularized in The Book: Playing the Percentages in Baseball, wOBA uses yearly MLB performance to weigh offensive measures relative to league value. This package offers the following capabilities:
 Retrieves the most up-to-date wOBA measures from 1871-2015 Queries yearly and career offensive performance from the Lahman SQL database Calculates a player&#39;s seasonal wOBA performance  Installation: Download the latest development version from github:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genre Interactive - Visualizing Video Games Throughout History</title>
      <link>/interactives/2015-06-10-genre-interactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/interactives/2015-06-10-genre-interactive/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theme Interactive - Visualizing Video Games Throughout History</title>
      <link>/interactives/2015-06-10-theme-interactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/interactives/2015-06-10-theme-interactive/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Video Games Throughout History</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-06-10-video-games-interactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2015-06-10-video-games-interactive/</guid>
      <description>Call of Duty :: Frank Underwood // Frogger :: George Costanza // Shinobi :: Wu-Tang Clan // Super Nintendo &amp;amp; Sega Genesis :: ??? That looks pretty sharp, but in the spirit of video games, lets make it a bit more&amp;hellip;8-bit.
I was also curious which themes were most likely to occur simultaneously. Think of the following interactive as such: &amp;ldquo;If I were to randomly select from the pool of Arcade games, what is the likelihood that it also has a _____ theme?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kris Bryant Performance Projection</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-03-25-bryant-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2015-03-25-bryant-visualization/</guid>
      <description>A dynamic rCharts visualization displaying performance projections for Kris Bryant based on his 10 most similar career MiLB comparable players. Read more at http://mikelee.co/posts/milb-similarity-scores/.
You can change the y-axis parameters by selecting the performance measure you’d like to visualize. Additionally, hover over the points to see player details, and select players in the legend to show or remove their data from the graph.
YearAgeLevEqGPAABRHX2BX3BHRRBISBCSBBSOBAOBPSLGOPSCount201523313054848976138325248394471050.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Minor League Similarity Scores</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-03-25-milb-similarity-scores/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2015-03-25-milb-similarity-scores/</guid>
      <description>Similarity scores were created by Bill James to compare the careers of Hall of Fame eligible players.In In the most basic sense, similarity scores use aggregated performance statistics to compare a player&#39;s worth for induction into the Hall of Fame. Projection systems follow from this method: Steamer, PECOTA, Marcel, ZiPS, and others use some combination of a player&#39;s recent performance, usually the last 3-4 seasons, to project future performance. Depending on the method, a player&#39;s base statistics are then modified using typical aging curves, linear weights, regression, and numerous other factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Make a Minor League Baseball Database!</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-02-23-milb-scraper-with-rvest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2015-02-23-milb-scraper-with-rvest/</guid>
      <description>To make our database we&#39;re going to use rvest, an R package designed by Hadley Wickham at RStudio [^1]. The package scrapes HTML from webpages and extracts it into readable data. Let&#39;s load the necessary packages and go from there:
#if you haven&amp;#39;t done so already, install rvest from Wickham&amp;#39;s github repository # install.packages(&amp;#34;devtools&amp;#34;) # install_github(&amp;#34;hadley/rvest&amp;#34;) c(&amp;#39;rvest&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;dplyr&amp;#39;) -&amp;gt; packages #installs packages lapply(packages, library, character.only = T)# prep scraper url &amp;lt;- &amp;#34;http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>