<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Michael Lee</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Michael Lee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick ggplot2 Tip: Creating Duplicate Legends</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-01-21-creating-duplicate-legends/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2020-01-21-creating-duplicate-legends/</guid>
      <description>Mastering the R package ggplot2The ggplot2 package provides powerful methods to display data as graphics. The beauty of the package lies in it’s simplicity - understanding the core methods (applying variables to aesthetics and transformations) covers ~95% of static visualizations a data visualization developer might be interested in generating. Most of final 5% can be achieved by understanding the infrastructure of the package. One such example is how plot components are “written” to the graphics device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick ggplot2 Tip: Left Align ggplot2 Titles, Subtitles, and Footnotes with Y-Axis Label</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-01-21-left-align-ggplot2-titles-subtitles-and-footnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2020-01-21-left-align-ggplot2-titles-subtitles-and-footnotes/</guid>
      <description>Mastering the R package ggplot2The ggplot2 package provides powerful methods to display data as graphics. The beauty of the package lies in it’s simplicity - understanding the core methods (applying variables to aesthetics and transformations) covers ~95% of static visualizations a data visualization developer might be interested in generating. Most of final 5% can be achieved by understanding the infrastructure of the package. One such example is how plot components are “written” to the graphics device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Animation Tip: Creating Pauses</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-02-23-creating-pauses-in-r-animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2019-02-23-creating-pauses-in-r-animations/</guid>
      <description>Mastering Animation in ROver the last couple years I’ve developed a multitude of animations using R. During this process I’ve learned quite a bit about R graphics, gpplot2, and useful techniques in animation. In fact I presented on methods for animation in R at satRdays DC - slides available here
One simple technique to improving animations is the addition of pauses. Pauses are an effective method of capturing the viewer’s attention and driving home the main message of an animation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dominance of Jonathan Taylor: Wisconsin Rushers in Context</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-01-28-wisconsin-rushing-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2019-01-28-wisconsin-rushing-history/</guid>
      <description>Hot Take Alert🔥 Jonathan Taylor is on pace to be the greatest running back in Wisconsin football history 🔥
Over the previous three decades Wisconsin has retained several elite rushers (and offensive lines) to amass several conference championships and Rose Bowl appearances. Even when acknowledging Taylor’s case as a serious Heisman candidate in each of his first two years, proclaiming him the presumptive best running back in Wisconsin football history still feels like a bold proclamation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seasonal Virgin River Narrows Discharge</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-04-16-hiking-the-narrows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2018-04-16-hiking-the-narrows/</guid>
      <description>This April I’m visiting Zion National Park, one of North America’s most interesting locations to explore geologic formations. One such venue in the park is an iconic hike referred to as The Narrows:
The Narrows in Zion National Park
It’s surely even more sensational in person.
Unfortunately, there’s a catch: the Virgin River, a Colorado river tributary that shaped the distinct rock walls of The Narrows, has seasonal water level changes that can force hikers to trek waist deep in the river or close the route entirely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wisconsin State Hex Grid - Mapping 2016 Presidential Results</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-11-16-wi-presidential-results-using-hexmapr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2017-11-16-wi-presidential-results-using-hexmapr/</guid>
      <description>NEAT PACKAGE ALERT!My 1st R package! https://t.co/dI3GJbC7FQ Automatically turn geospatial polygons like states into regular/hexagonal grids #rstats #ggplot2 pic.twitter.com/dxvYCZWJzU— J Bailey (@iammrbailey) October 31, 2017I’ve been thinking about implementing something like this for a while - got excited by this tweet I thought I would do some exploring and write out a post over the weekend. Creating a county-level hex grid of Wisconsin makes for a perfect supplment to my earlier post about mapping the 2016 Wisconsin presidential results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Makeover Monday: WSJ Measles Vaccination Chart</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-07-10-makeover-monday-wsj-measles-vaccination-chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2017-07-10-makeover-monday-wsj-measles-vaccination-chart/</guid>
      <description>Last week I wrote a post about recreating the WSJ measles vaccination chart as an animated cartogram - you can check out the full write-up of the development here: www.mikelee.co/posts/2017-06-28-wsj-measles-vaccination-chart/
It was featured on DataCamp across all their social media platforms - pretty neat!
A comment from one of the readers (which disqus seems to have overwritten as I was re-initializing my site) read as so:
Your measles chart is a beautiful piece of work!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animated Line Chart from Condition of Education 2017 Data Release</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-06-28-animated-line-chart-coe-bullying/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2017-06-28-animated-line-chart-coe-bullying/</guid>
      <description>Animation seen here!New from #COE2017: 21% of students reported being bullied at school in 2015, a ↓ from the 28% reported in 2005. https://t.co/5BlyLdHS9W pic.twitter.com/Fr1pTt8xca— NCES (@EdNCES) May 3, 2017Full image:COE 2017 Bullying Line Graph Animation
Interested in learning more? Hire me to consult on your next project, follow me on twitter, leave a comment, or contact me via email. All inquiries welcome!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducing the WSJ Measles Vaccination Chart Using R</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-06-28-wsj-measles-vaccination-chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2017-06-28-wsj-measles-vaccination-chart/</guid>
      <description>Mastering Animation in RUPDATE: In order to reproduce some portions of this code you need the gganimate package using the deprecated API. To access that version, download v0.1.1 here.
Recently I’ve been working on creating gif animations for social media:
New from #COE2017: 21% of students reported being bullied at school in 2015, a ↓ from the 28% reported in 2005. https://t.co/5BlyLdHS9W pic.twitter.com/Fr1pTt8xca— NCES (@EdNCES) May 3, 2017It’s pretty addicting!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Wisconsin Presidential Election Results</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-12-26-wisconsin-presidential-election-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2016-12-26-wisconsin-presidential-election-results/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Your home state did us no favors&amp;hellip;&amp;quot; As a Wisconsinite transplanted into the highest density of left-leaning voters in the country (District of Columbia) I&#39;ve heard from several friends over the weeks in the aftermath of the US presidential election that voters in my home state should shoulder responsibility for contributing to Donald Trump winning an electoral majority.
The &amp;ldquo;winner-take-all&amp;rdquo; basis in which electoral votes are allocated means the margin of victory in each state is null - extra votes don&#39;t matter - which contributes to an outcome in which a winning candidate can have fewer total votes than another nominee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NBA Draft Odds Plot</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-06-01-nba-draft-odds-plot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2016-06-01-nba-draft-odds-plot/</guid>
      <description>Original Source
I was scrolling twitter and noticed this tweet from David Sparks - Director of Basketball Analytics for the Boston Celtics:
With his obligatory shoutouts to Hadley Wickham and BoB Rudis, I felt compelled to reproduce the plot in RStudio and get some ggplot2 code out there open-sourcing his work.
Package Dependencies and Data
The data was generated using simulations of the NBA Draft lottery, which resulted in some peculiar distributions compared to the raw lottery odds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mikelee.co: Powered by RMarkdown, knitr, and Jekyll</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-05-24-mikeleeco-powered-by-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2016-05-24-mikeleeco-powered-by-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
 Spend a few months documenting code scripts in RStudio and you&#39;ll have surely seen those introductory lines numerous times.
This is also a R code script. And a markdown document. And an HTML page. All of which are generated within one .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sabr - R package</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-05-28-sabr-r-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2016-05-28-sabr-r-package/</guid>
      <description>The sabr package connects the Lahman SQL Database with functions used in calculating offensive performance in the MLB, namely wOBA. Created by Tom Tango and popularized in The Book: Playing the Percentages in Baseball, wOBA uses yearly MLB performance to weigh offensive measures relative to league value. This package offers the following capabilities:
 Retrieves the most up-to-date wOBA measures from 1871-2015 Queries yearly and career offensive performance from the Lahman SQL database Calculates a player&#39;s seasonal wOBA performance  Installation: Download the latest development version from github:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Video Games Throughout History</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-06-10-video-games-interactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2015-06-10-video-games-interactive/</guid>
      <description>Call of Duty :: Frank Underwood // Frogger :: George Costanza // Shinobi :: Wu-Tang Clan // Super Nintendo &amp;amp; Sega Genesis :: ??? That looks pretty sharp, but in the spirit of video games, lets make it a bit more&amp;hellip;8-bit.
I was also curious which themes were most likely to occur simultaneously. Think of the following interactive as such: &amp;ldquo;If I were to randomly select from the pool of Arcade games, what is the likelihood that it also has a _____ theme?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kris Bryant Performance Projection</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-03-25-bryant-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2015-03-25-bryant-visualization/</guid>
      <description>A dynamic rCharts visualization displaying performance projections for Kris Bryant based on his 10 most similar career MiLB comparable players. Read more at http://mikelee.co/posts/milb-similarity-scores/.
You can change the y-axis parameters by selecting the performance measure you’d like to visualize. Additionally, hover over the points to see player details, and select players in the legend to show or remove their data from the graph.
YearAgeLevEqGPAABRHX2BX3BHRRBISBCSBBSOBAOBPSLGOPSCount201523313054848976138325248394471050.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Minor League Similarity Scores</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-03-25-milb-similarity-scores/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2015-03-25-milb-similarity-scores/</guid>
      <description>Similarity scores were created by Bill James to compare the careers of Hall of Fame eligible players.In In the most basic sense, similarity scores use aggregated performance statistics to compare a player&#39;s worth for induction into the Hall of Fame. Projection systems follow from this method: Steamer, PECOTA, Marcel, ZiPS, and others use some combination of a player&#39;s recent performance, usually the last 3-4 seasons, to project future performance. Depending on the method, a player&#39;s base statistics are then modified using typical aging curves, linear weights, regression, and numerous other factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Make a Minor League Baseball Database!</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-02-23-milb-scraper-with-rvest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2015-02-23-milb-scraper-with-rvest/</guid>
      <description>To make our database we&#39;re going to use rvest, an R package designed by Hadley Wickham at RStudio [^1]. The package scrapes HTML from webpages and extracts it into readable data. Let&#39;s load the necessary packages and go from there:
#if you haven&amp;#39;t done so already, install rvest from Wickham&amp;#39;s github repository # install.packages(&amp;#34;devtools&amp;#34;) # install_github(&amp;#34;hadley/rvest&amp;#34;) c(&amp;#39;rvest&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;dplyr&amp;#39;) -&amp;gt; packages #installs packages lapply(packages, library, character.only = T)# prep scraper url &amp;lt;- &amp;#34;http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>