<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sports on Michael Lee</title>
    <link>/tags/sports/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sports on Michael Lee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/sports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dominance of Jonathan Taylor: Wisconsin Rushers in Context</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-01-28-wisconsin-rushing-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2019-01-28-wisconsin-rushing-history/</guid>
      <description>Hot Take Alert🔥 Jonathan Taylor is on pace to be the greatest running back in Wisconsin football history 🔥
Over the previous three decades Wisconsin has retained several elite rushers (and offensive lines) to amass several conference championships and Rose Bowl appearances. Even when acknowledging Taylor’s case as a serious Heisman candidate in each of his first two years, proclaiming him the presumptive best running back in Wisconsin football history still feels like a bold proclamation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kris Bryant Performance Projection</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-03-25-bryant-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2015-03-25-bryant-visualization/</guid>
      <description>A dynamic rCharts visualization displaying performance projections for Kris Bryant based on his 10 most similar career MiLB comparable players. Read more at http://mikelee.co/posts/milb-similarity-scores/.
You can change the y-axis parameters by selecting the performance measure you’d like to visualize. Additionally, hover over the points to see player details, and select players in the legend to show or remove their data from the graph.
YearAgeLevEqGPAABRHX2BX3BHRRBISBCSBBSOBAOBPSLGOPSCount201523313054848976138325248394471050.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Minor League Similarity Scores</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-03-25-milb-similarity-scores/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2015-03-25-milb-similarity-scores/</guid>
      <description>Similarity scores were created by Bill James to compare the careers of Hall of Fame eligible players.In In the most basic sense, similarity scores use aggregated performance statistics to compare a player&#39;s worth for induction into the Hall of Fame. Projection systems follow from this method: Steamer, PECOTA, Marcel, ZiPS, and others use some combination of a player&#39;s recent performance, usually the last 3-4 seasons, to project future performance. Depending on the method, a player&#39;s base statistics are then modified using typical aging curves, linear weights, regression, and numerous other factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Make a Minor League Baseball Database!</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-02-23-milb-scraper-with-rvest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/posts/2015-02-23-milb-scraper-with-rvest/</guid>
      <description>To make our database we&#39;re going to use rvest, an R package designed by Hadley Wickham at RStudio [^1]. The package scrapes HTML from webpages and extracts it into readable data. Let&#39;s load the necessary packages and go from there:
#if you haven&amp;#39;t done so already, install rvest from Wickham&amp;#39;s github repository # install.packages(&amp;#34;devtools&amp;#34;) # install_github(&amp;#34;hadley/rvest&amp;#34;) c(&amp;#39;rvest&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;dplyr&amp;#39;) -&amp;gt; packages #installs packages lapply(packages, library, character.only = T)# prep scraper url &amp;lt;- &amp;#34;http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>