<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Animation on Michael Lee</title>
    <link>/categories/animation/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Animation on Michael Lee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="/categories/animation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Makeover Monday: WSJ Measles Vaccination Chart</title>
      <link>/animation/2017-07-10-makeover-monday-wsj-measles-vaccination-chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/animation/2017-07-10-makeover-monday-wsj-measles-vaccination-chart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I wrote a post about recreating the WSJ measles vaccination chart as an animated cartogram - you can check out the full write-up of the development here: &lt;a href=&#34;www.mikelee.co/posts/2017-06-28-wsj-measles-vaccination-chart/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;www.mikelee.co/posts/2017-06-28-wsj-measles-vaccination-chart/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was featured on DataCamp across all their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:6288400911173709824&#34;&gt;social&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DataCamp/status/882634632935735296&#34;&gt;media&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=1656557754368698&amp;amp;id=726282547396228&#34;&gt;platforms&lt;/a&gt; - pretty neat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A comment from one of the readers (which disqus seems to have overwritten as I was re-initializing my site) read as so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your measles chart is a beautiful piece of work! No question. The (vertical) sorting merely by alphabetic state listing, however, adds nothing to the information. Even better, I think, would be to place these stats on a US map. The animation would then show the geographic progress of the disease. Try first on a state basis; counties would be too confusing The ultimate presentation, however, would show the importance of high population densities (metropolitan areas). - Kenneth Holland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s an interesting idea Kenneth!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder whether a similar type of graphic representation was considered by the WSJ authors. Either way, this is a great excuse to jump on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.makeovermonday.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Makeover Monday&lt;/a&gt; train.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;makeover-the-wsj-measles-incidence-visualization-as-a-cartogram&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Makeover the WSJ Measles Incidence Visualization as a Cartogram&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that I’ve already completed the data acquisition and manipulation in my previous post, I’ll jump right into plotting the state level data. The county-level piece is an interesting idea, but I’ll leave that for someone else!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the final result:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/measlesCartogram.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Measles Animation Cartogram&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Measles Animation Cartogram&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I customized the plot in a few ways - first, I chose to represent the change in time via a timeline above the cartogram. Other developers have represented change in time using years as text - such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/a2BEHjL.gif&#34;&gt;Financial Times’ income distribution gif&lt;/a&gt; (their original post &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ft.com/content/98ce14ee-99a6-11e5-95c7-d47aa298f769?mhq5j=e2&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I selected a moving dot for a few reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;given the large selection of years, a frequently changing portion of the image would be a distraction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the movement of the dot is an intuitive representation of change over time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the point could be encoded with data - the color represents the national mean incidence!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final product is a quality alternative to the WSJ’s original visualization, though I prefer the original representation as a full grid over years - the drastic reduction in measles incidence is more impactful with 30+ years of negligible incidence stacked up next to each other. Have other thoughts? Leave them in the comments - hopefully disqus doesn’t delete em this time :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested in learning more? Hire me to consult on your next project, follow me on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mikeleeco&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;, leave a comment, or contact me via &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:mdlee12@gmail.com&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;. All inquiries welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>