<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>automated reports on Michael Lee</title>
    <link>/tags/automated-reports/</link>
    <description>Recent content in automated reports on Michael Lee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/automated-reports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Reports - Nevada Department of Education</title>
      <link>/projects/2019-12-30-automated-report-nevada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/projects/2019-12-30-automated-report-nevada/</guid>
      <description>Background Each Fall and Spring the Nevada Department of Education disseminates a summary report detailing results from a social-emotional learning survey. The report uses a standard template populated with customized text, data values, and data visualizations. Previous productions of these reports were created by a separate contractor. One such example is linked here.
Development The goal for this project was to automate the production of each school&#39;s customized report. One special (read: complex) consideration of this report generation was a requirement for 508 compliance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Reports - Cleveland Metropolitan School District</title>
      <link>/projects/2018-11-20-automated-report-cleveland-metropolitan-school-district/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/projects/2018-11-20-automated-report-cleveland-metropolitan-school-district/</guid>
      <description>Background Each Fall and Spring the Cleveland Metropolitan School District disseminates a summary report detailing results from a survey assessing four social-emotional learning constructs within elementary, middle and high schools. The report uses a standard template populated with customized text, data values, and data visualizations. Previous productions of these reports were created by a separate contractor; one such example is linked here.
Development The goal for this project was to automate the production of each school&#39;s customized report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Reports - IMLS, Public Libraries Survey</title>
      <link>/projects/2018-05-09-automated-reports-public-library-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mdlee12@gmail.com (Michael Lee)</author>
      <guid>/projects/2018-05-09-automated-reports-public-library-services/</guid>
      <description>Background The Institute of Museum and Library Services&amp;rsquo; mission is to inspire libraries and museums to advance innovation, lifelong learning, and cultural and civic engagement. Each year it conducts a survey of the nation’s approximately 123,000 libraries and 35,000 museums to provide a snapshot of national and state-level trends.
Development The goal for this project was to automate the production of each state and jurisdiction&#39;s customized report. I acted as an R and LaTeX developer in creation of the template laying out these summary results.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>